Emmanuel Jolugbo

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Experienced Full Stack Software Developer with a background in Computer Science and over 4 years of freelance experience. Specializing in ReactJS, NEXTJS, TypeScript, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails with Postgres, and Node.js. Eager to join an innovative tech team to contribute both technical expertise and strong interpersonal skills. Actively seeking opportunities to work on challenging projects and further enhance my professional capabilities.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance, Remote

Software Engineer

- Developed New Enterprise Software and implemented new features.
- Effectively deployed solutions on servers within the organization's network.
- Troubleshoot problems, debugged, and corrected service and application issues.

MICROVERSE. Remote

Mentor (Volunteer), FEB, 2022 - AUG 2022

- Mentoring junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews
- Proposing improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Providing advice and tips on maintaining motivation and longevity in the program.

Dinero Cities and Structural Limited, Lagos, Nigeria

MIS Unit, Feb 2020 - May 2022

- Designed front-end designs with HTML and CSS.
- Effectively deployed solutions on servers within the organization's network.
- Created Designs for social media posts.

BaseAfrique, Lagos, Nigeria

Software Engineer, June 2019 - December 2021

- Developed New Enterprise Software and implemented new features.
- Effectively deployed solutions on servers within the organization's network.
- Troubleshoot problems, debugged, and corrected service and application issues.

Nouveau Riche Media Technologies LTD, Lagos, Nigeria

Intern, November 2018-April 2019

- Worked closely with designers to recreate front-end designs with HTML and CSS (SCSS) to soothe design mockups and prototypes
- Participated in the definition of crucial scenarios, use cases, and end-user experience.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE, Jan 2022 - August 2022

Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

lamthermiee@gmail.com GitHub | LinkedIn Twitter | AngelList Portfolio +2348139319274

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, Typescript, React, Redux, Nextjs, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, WordPress.

Back-end: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Node.js.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools.

Soft skills: Pair programming, Remote development, Deadlines, Mentoring, and Teamwork.

Testing: Jest, Capybara, RSpec.

PROJECTS

Lola Finance -2023

- Lola helps you communicate, discover new ideas, process payments and more as a community.
- Built with (Nextjs, Redux, Typescript, and TailwindCSS)

Assetize -2023

- This platform ensures the security of your investments. What sets it apart is the unique opportunity to own fractionalized investments, enabling you to diversify your portfolio effortlessly
- Built with (Reacvt, Typescript, Tailwind, and Redux)

Math-magicians -2021

- It is a Single Page App (SPA) that allows users to make simple calculations and read random math-related quotes.
- Built with (React, React-router)

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing coding projects including front-end, back-end, and full-stack projects using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, HTML, and CSS -- and included unit testing when applicable.
- Full-time program that required work across time zones while pair-programming with other software engineers worldwide.
- Leveraged Agile methodologies requiring excellent communication skills to share project status updates, plan daily workflow, create solid documentation, and attend daily standups.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

NIIT NIGERIA, Jan 2017 - 2018

Diploma in Java Enterprises Apps with DevOps, Full time.

- Creating software engineering professionals in Java Technologies.
- Spent 1300+ hours mastering, RDMS Essential & T-SQL Programming, Programming in JAVA, HTML 5 and Responsive Web Design, Developing Web Applications using Servlets & JSP, Implementing JSF, Hibernate, and Springs in J2EE Applications, GIT & GITHUB, Testing with JUnit, and DevOps
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Space-Travelers-Hub -2021

- The web application provides commercial and scientific space travel services. The application will allow users to book rockets and join selected space missions using accurate live data from the SpaceX API.
- Built with (React, and React-router)